The following content is provided
提供以下内容
under a Creative Commons license.
根据知识共享许可。
Your support will help MIT OpenCourseWare continue
您的支持将帮助MIT OpenCourseWare继续
to offer high quality educational resources for free.
免费提供高质量的教育资源。
To make a donation or view additional materials
捐款或查看其他材料
from hundreds of MIT courses, visit MIT OpenCourseWare
从数百门麻省理工学院的课程中，访问MIT OpenCourseWare
at ocw.mit.edu.
在ocw.mit.edu。
PROFESSOR: Are people understanding AVLs?
教授：人们了解AVL吗？
That's good, because if everyone raised their hands,
很好，因为如果每个人都举手，
we'd be done and out of here.
我们会做完的，然后离开这里。
So we're not covering new material in this recitation.
因此，本次朗诵不涉及新材料。
We're talking about AVLs again, except this time
除了这次，我们再次谈论AVL
you'll tell me how we'll do them,
你会告诉我我们将如何做，
and we'll look at the code and see
然后我们看一下代码，看看
how the theory matches the code.
理论如何与代码匹配。
And I need one of these.
我需要其中之一。
Thank you.
谢谢。
So let's start simple.
让我们开始吧。
What's a BST?
什么是BST？
AUDIENCE: Binary search tree.
受众：二进制搜索树。
PROFESSOR: OK, binary search tree.
教授：好的，二进制搜索树。
It's binary because every node has at most two children.
它是二进制的，因为每个节点最多有两个孩子。
Why is it a search tree?
为什么是搜索树？
AUDIENCE: It's easy to search.
听众：很容易搜索。
PROFESSOR: OK.
教授：好的。
Why is it easy to search?
为什么搜索容易？
AUDIENCE: Because you start [INAUDIBLE],
听众：因为您开始[听不清]，
is my number greater than this key or is it less than,
我的数字大于此键还是小于，
and then you go from there.
然后你从那里去。
PROFESSOR: OK.
教授：好的。
So if I would have to state this as a formal rep invariant
因此，如果我不得不将其声明为正式代表不变式
thing, what would I say it is so that I can do that operation?
事情，我要说的是什么以便我可以执行该操作？
AUDIENCE: Node at right is greater than
听众：右侧的节点大于
node at key, which is greater than node at left.
关键点处的节点，大于左边的节点。
PROFESSOR: OK, excellent.
教授：好的，很好。
So it turns out I can use this argument recursively
所以事实证明我可以递归使用这个参数
to say that for a given node, everything that
表示对于给定的节点，
is to the right of that node is greater,
在那个节点的右边更大
and everything that is to the left is smaller.
左侧的所有内容都较小。
And this allows us to do search quickly
这使我们可以快速进行搜索
because if you're looking for a key,
因为如果您正在寻找钥匙，
say you have numbers in your tree and you're looking for 5.
说您的树上有数字，并且正在寻找5。
If you arrive at a node whose value is 4, you go right.
如果到达值为4的节点，则继续进行。
If you arrive at a node whose value is 7, you go left.
如果到达值为7的节点，则向左走。
OK So what do we know how to do on BSTs?
好，那么我们知道如何在BST上做什么？
What are the operations that we know?
我们知道什么操作？
AUDIENCE: Minimum, maximum.
听众：最小，最大。
PROFESSOR: Min, max.
教授：最小，最大
AUDIENCE: Left, right, parent.
听众：左，右，父母。
PROFESSOR: So those are for the node.
教授：这些是用于节点的。
I want the queries and the updates for the BST type.
我想要查询和BST类型的更新。
AUDIENCE: Insert and delete.
听众：插入和删除。
PROFESSOR: OK.
教授：好的。
Insert, Delete.
插入，删除。
AUDIENCE: Next larger.
听众：接下来更大。
PROFESSOR: OK.
教授：好的。
And then in here, the S in BST.
然后是BST中的S
Someone give me the S so we can move on.
有人给我S，以便我们继续前进。
AUDIENCE: Find.
听众：找到。
PROFESSOR: Find, search, depending
教授：根据需要查找，搜索
on what code you're reading.
您正在阅读的代码。
What's the running time for these guys?
这些家伙的跑步时间是多少？
AUDIENCE: Order h.
听众：订单h。
PROFESSOR: Excellent.
教授：非常好。
So everything has the same running time.
因此，所有内容都具有相同的运行时间。
Nice and easy to remember.
很容易记住。
Order h.
订单h。
What's h?
什么啊
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE].
听众：[听不清]。
PROFESSOR: OK.
教授：好的。
How do we define this height?
我们如何定义这个高度？
What's the height for this tree?
这棵树的高度是多少？
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE].
听众：[听不清]。
PROFESSOR: Good.
教授：很好。
What's the height for this tree?
这棵树的高度是多少？
AUDIENCE: Two.
听众：两个。
PROFESSOR: So now for a more general case,
教授：所以现在来看一个更一般的情况，
where this is the height, and the height of my left subtree
这是我的左子树的高度和高度
is hl.
是hl。
The height of my right subtree is hr.
我右边的子树的高度是hr。
What's h?
什么啊
AUDIENCE: It's the maximum of hr times hl plus 1.
听众：这是hr乘以hl加上1的最大值。
PROFESSOR: Nice save.
教授：很好。
I heard a "plus 1" somewhere there.
我在那里听到“加1”。
Very good.
很好。
This is r.
这是r。
So if we look at the first part of the code,
因此，如果我们看一下代码的第一部分，
lines one through eight, lines seven and eight
第一到第八行，第七和第八行
implement the definition that we talked about here.
实现我们在这里讨论的定义。
So in our Python implementation, each node
因此，在我们的Python实现中，每个节点
knows the height of the tree that he's the root of.
知道他是根的那棵树的高度。
And since we're storing that, we need
既然我们要存储它，我们需要
to update it every once in awhile when we make changes
在进行更改时每隔一段时间进行更新
to the tree, like when we insert nodes.
就像我们插入节点时一样。
And the way we do that is update height, which
我们这样做的方法是更新高度
uses the formula that we came up with here.
使用我们在这里想到的公式。
Now, there is a hack on lines two, three, four, five.
现在，在第二，第三，第四，第五行有一个破解。
Can anyone tell me what the hack is?
谁能告诉我骇客是什么？
AUDIENCE: The negative 1.
听众：负面1。
PROFESSOR: OK.
教授：好的。
How does that work?
这是如何运作的？
Why do I need it?
我为什么需要它？
AUDIENCE: That's so if you're at the root node,
听众：就是这样，如果您在根节点上，
you can still calculate the height.
您仍然可以计算高度。
PROFESSOR: Depends on how the root node looks like.
教授：取决于根节点的外观。
AUDIENCE: If it has no children.
听众：如果没有孩子。
PROFESSOR: That's a leaf.
教授：那是一片叶子。
AUDIENCE: Yes.
听众：是的。
PROFESSOR: OK.
教授：好的。
So if I'm in this case or in this case, what's hl,
因此，如果我在这种情况下还是在这种情况下，hl是什么，
what's hr?
什么时间？
In this case, I have this node of height zero,
在这种情况下，我有这个高度为零的节点，
so I can make a small mistake here and it'll save me,
所以我可以在这里犯一个小错误，这样可以救我，
but here, I have no children, so hl and hr have
但是在这里，我没有孩子，所以hl和hr有
to be set in such a way that this formula evaluates to 0.
设置为使该公式的值为0。
If I set them to minus 1, I'll have minus 1, minus 1.
如果将它们设置为负1，我将具有负1，负1。
The maximum is minus 1 plus 1 equals 0.
最大值为负1加1等于0。
AUDIENCE: It's just to check the nodes for AVLs.
听众：只是检查节点的AVL。
PROFESSOR: We use that to update the height.
教授：我们用它来更新高度。
For AVLs, we need to know the height
对于AVL，我们需要知道高度
of a node instantaneously.
瞬间
We can't afford to go down the tree
我们买不起那棵树
and compute the height every time we need it,
并在每次需要时计算高度
so every node gets to store its height.
这样每个节点都可以存储其高度。
There's a small field in each node that has the height.
每个节点中都有一个高度小的字段。
So we need to update that every once in awhile when
因此，我们需要每隔一段时间更新一次
we do insertions and deletions.
我们进行插入和删除。
This is how we update it, and in order
这就是我们如何更新它，并按顺序
to update it for this case, where we're at a leaf,
为这种情况更新它，我们在一片叶子上，
we have to say that the height of a non-existing tree
我们必须说一棵不存在的树的高度
is minus 1.
为负1。
Of course, in theory and in real life,
当然，在理论上和现实生活中，
there are no non-existing trees, so this is a clever hack
没有不存在的树，所以这是一个聪明的技巧
to reduce code size.
减少代码大小。
So we said binary search trees would look something like this.
所以我们说二进制搜索树看起来像这样。
Is this guy an AVL?
这个人是AVL吗？
Does anyone think it's an a AVL?
有人认为这是AVL吗？
Does anyone think it's not an AVL?
有人认为这不是AVL吗？
Can one of you tell me why?
谁能告诉我为什么？
AUDIENCE: The tree with 5 as its root is not balanced.
听众：以5为根的树是不平衡的。
PROFESSOR: So this guy here is not balanced.
教授：所以这个人不平衡。
Why is it not balanced?
为什么不平衡？
AUDIENCE: Because it has two on its right and zero on its left,
听众：因为它的右边有两个，左边有零，
so the difference is greater than 1.
所以差异大于1。
PROFESSOR: You're saying that there's something here
教授：您是说这里有些事
that's two, and something here that's-- OK, so height.
那是两个，这里的东西是-好，那么高。
So then it's almost like that.
这样就差不多了。
It's 1 here and minus 1 here.
这里是1，这里是1。
So the reason I asked you to clarify
所以我要求你澄清的原因
is that first you said two and zero,
首先是你说二和零，
and that's the node count, and AVL
这是节点数和AVL
doesn't care about node count.
不在乎节点数。
AVL cares about height.
AVL关心身高。
So for example, if I have something like this,
例如，如果我有这样的事情，
this is a happy AVL.
这是一个快乐的AVL。
Three nodes, here one node here.
三个节点，这里一个节点。
The difference in node count is greater than 1,
节点数之差大于1，
but the difference in height is 1.
但高度差为1。
Therefore, this is a good AVL.
因此，这是一个很好的AVL。
So what's a rep invariant for an AVL?
那么，AVL的代表不变性是什么？
AUDIENCE: The height of the left subtree for every node
听众：每个节点的左子树的高度
is within 1 of the height of the right subtree.
在右子树的高度的1之内。
PROFESSOR: Excellent.
教授：非常好。
AVL.
AVL。
The core property is that for every node,
核心属性是每个节点
the left height and the right height differ by at most 1.
左高度和右高度最多相差1。
What else?
还有什么？
If we want to be completely rigorous,
如果我们要严格一点
what else do we have to say?
我们还要说什么？
It's a BST.
这是BST。
So an AVL is a special kind of BST,
因此，AVL是一种特殊的BST，
and that's why when we write the AVL code,
这就是为什么当我们编写AVL代码时，
we inherit from the BST and we use some of its methods
我们从BST继承而来，并使用了一些方法
heavily.
沉重。
Why do we like AVLs?
为什么我们喜欢AVL？
What's so good about them?
他们有什么好处？
AUDIENCE: It's faster because it ensures the minimal height
观众：速度更快，因为它可以确保最小的高度
of the entire tree because most of our complexities are o of h,
因为我们大多数的复杂性都是h的o，
so it would have to be smaller.
因此它必须更小。
PROFESSOR: So we care about this.
教授：因此，我们对此表示关注。
In a regular binary tree, the worst case that you have
在常规的二叉树中，最糟糕的情况是
is this.
这是。
Ignoring this part, this is a worst case binary search tree
忽略这部分，这是最坏情况的二进制搜索树
where it's basically a list, so height is order n.
它基本上是一个列表，因此高度为n阶。
In an AVL, you're saying it's better.
在AVL中，您说的更好。
So the reason why we care about AVLs is
因此，我们关心AVL的原因是
that height is order of log n.
该高度是对数n的顺序。
Now, did people understand from lecture why that's the case?
现在，人们从演讲中了解为什么会这样吗？
Can anyone tell me why that's the case?
谁能告诉我为什么会这样吗？
AUDIENCE: Well, it's just like every level
听众：好吧，就像每个级别
you go down, if you split off that many times, of course
你走下去，如果你分裂了那么多次，当然
it's log n.
它是日志n。
If you have n nodes and they're filled up to the edge,
如果您有n个节点并且它们已被填满，
there's going to be log n of them.
他们将要登录n。
AUDIENCE: It's close to a full binary tree, right?
听众：它接近完整的二叉树，对吗？
PROFESSOR: For some definition of "close."
教授：关于“关闭”的定义。
So here's what I use to remember,
所以这就是我要记住的
and I think I can persuade you that the height is log n using
我想我可以说服您使用
the argument that I'll show you here.
我将在这里向您展示的论点。
Let's start building a tree this way.
让我们以这种方式开始构建树。
Let's say I have a fixed height, and I
假设我有固定的身高，而我
want to have as few nodes as possible.
希望拥有尽可能少的节点。
If I have a tree with a big height and very few nodes,
如果我有一棵高大的树，只有很少的节点，
h is going to be bad when you write it as a function of n.
当您将其写为n的函数时，h将是不好的。
So those trees are unbalanced.
所以那些树是不平衡的。
Big height, small number of nodes.
高度大，节点数少。
So say we're trying to build an AVL with the smallest
所以说我们正在尝试用最小的AVL
number of nodes and a fixed height.
节点数和固定高度。
What if the height is 0?
如果高度为0怎么办？
What does that tree look like?
那棵树是什么样的？
It's not too complicated, right?
不太复杂吧？
This is an AVL of height 0.
这是高度为0的AVL。
It's the only possible AVL of height 0.
这是高度0的唯一可能的AVL。
Now, what if we're trying to build an AVL of height 1
现在，如果我们要构建高度为1的AVL怎么办
that has as few nodes as possible?
有尽可能少的节点？
This is what it looks like, right?
看起来像这样吧？
Height 0, height 1.
高度0，高度1。
I could add another node here, but I
我可以在这里添加另一个节点，但是我
don't want to because I want as few nodes as possible.
不想，因为我想要尽可能少的节点。
Now, what if I tried to build an AVL of height 2
现在，如果我尝试构建高度为2的AVL怎么办
that has as few nodes as possible?
有尽可能少的节点？
Can I do this?
我可以这样做吗？
AUDIENCE: So at the worst case, you have h minus 1
听众：所以在最坏的情况下，你的h减1
and then h minus 2 there.
然后h减2。
PROFESSOR: OK.
教授：好的。
You're moving ahead.
您正在前进。
You're forcing me to move faster, but you're right.
您逼我加快步伐，但您是对的。
And the reason is this is unbalanced.
原因是这是不平衡的。
The height at the left has to be the height of the right
左边的高度必须是右边的高度
plus or minus 1.
正负1。
Can't be anything else.
别无其他。
So at the very least, I have to build a tree of height 0 here,
因此，至少我必须在此处建造一棵高度为0的树，
and I know that the best tree of height
我知道最好的树高
0 that I have is this guy.
我有0是这个人。
Cool.
凉。
So for height 3, I would have to do this.
因此，对于高度3，我将必须执行此操作。
And then you're saying, what would I use at the left?
然后您说的是，我将在左侧使用什么？
AUDIENCE: You'd use whatever height's on the right minus 2.
听众：您可以使用右侧减去2的任何高度。
The height on the right minus 1 per side.
右侧的高度每侧减去1。
PROFESSOR: So on the right, I have a height 2.
教授：所以在右边，我的身高是2。
On the left, I have a height 1.
在左边，我的身高是1。
If I want to go up to height 4, I do the same thing.
如果我想上升到4号高度，我会做同样的事情。
So if I want to build an AVL tree
所以如果我想建立一个AVL树
with as few nodes as possible and height h,
尽可能少的节点和高度h
I start with the root, then at the right,
我从根开始，然后在右边，
I build an AVL tree of height h minus 1, and at the left,
我建立了高度为h减去1的AVL树，在左侧，
an AVL tree of height h minus 2.
高度为h减去2.的AVL树。
And if these have the minimum number of nodes,
如果这些节点的数量最少，
then it turns out that the whole thing
然后事实证明整个事情
has the minimum number of nodes.
节点数最少。
I don't want to build a tree where the heights are
我不想在高处建一棵树
equal because that would mean more nodes here,
相等，因为这意味着此处有更多节点，
so this is the best I can do.
所以这是我所能做的最好的。
This is the best way I can build a tall tree
这是我建高大树的最好方法
with as few nodes as possible.
节点越少越好。
Suppose I want to write the number of nodes
假设我要写节点数
as a function of height.
作为高度的函数。
You're telling me what it is.
你是在告诉我这是什么。
When I was here, you were giving me the answer for this.
当我在这里时，您正在给我答案。
So suppose I have a height, and I
所以假设我有个身高
want to know how many nodes I have in my tree that
想知道我的树上有多少个节点
has a minimum number of nodes.
节点数最少。
What is it?
它是什么？
AUDIENCE: It's N h minus 1, and then plus N h minus 2.
听众：是N h减去1，然后加上N h减去2。
There might be a constant.
可能有一个常数。
PROFESSOR: There might be a constant.
教授：可能有一个常数。
N h minus 1 is this tree, N h minus 2 is this tree,
N h减1是这棵树，N h减2是这棵树，
so what's the constant?
那么什么是常数？
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE].
听众：[听不清]。
PROFESSOR: Yep.
教授：是的。
This guy.
这家伙。
AUDIENCE: Doesn't he have height 0, though?
听众：不过他不是有0身高吗？
AUDIENCE: We're talking number of nodes.
听众：我们在谈论节点数。
AUDIENCE: Oh.
听众：哦。
Number of nodes, yeah.
节点数，是的。
PROFESSOR: I'm not going to solve this now.
教授：我现在不打算解决这个问题。
We learned how to solve recurrences a long time ago,
我们很久以前就学会了如何解决复发问题，
so I'll pretend I still remember how to do that,
所以我假装我仍然记得该怎么做，
and I will tell you that the solution looks
我会告诉你解决方案看起来
something like this.
这样的事情。
N of h is roughly 5, which is the magic number that we talked
h的N大约为5，这是我们所说的幻数
about in lecture-- roughly, which
大概在演讲中
means there might be some things there that I forgot-- to the h.
意味着可能有一些我忘了的东西-h。
What really matters is that it's an exponential in h.
真正重要的是，它是h的指数。
If you look at these guys, this is close to the Fibonacci
如果你看这些家伙，这跟斐波那契很接近
number formula except there's a plus 1 here.
数字公式，除了这里有一个加号1。
So these guys are bigger than the Fibonacci numbers.
因此，这些人比斐波那契数更大。
This is definitely bigger than whatever
绝对比什么都大
the formula for Fibonacci numbers
斐波那契数的公式
is, which is 5 to the h minus something over something.
是，即5减去h减去某物。
What really matters is the minimum number of nodes
真正重要的是最小节点数
in an AVL of height h is an exponential as a function of h.
在高度AVL中，h是h的指数。
If you invert that, you get that the maximum height
如果将其反转，则得到最大高度
for a tree with N nodes is log N. This is a way
对于具有N个节点的树，则为logN。这是一种方法
to construct an AVL that shows you that the height has
构造一个AVL，向您显示高度
to be logarithmic as long as we can keep this rep
只要我们能保持这个代表就可以对数
invariant true.
不变的。
AUDIENCE: I have a question.
听众：我有一个问题。
I didn't quite follow how you got h minus 2 and h minus 1
我不太了解你如何得到h减2和h减1
there.
那里。
PROFESSOR: Here, here, here?
教授：在这里，在这里？
AUDIENCE: There.
听众：在那里。
The tree down.
树倒了。
This one?
这个？
AUDIENCE: This one, yeah.
听众：是的。
PROFESSOR: OK.
教授：好的。
So suppose I'm at height 4 here.
因此，假设我的身高为4。
What's the best way to construct an AVL that
构造AVL的最佳方法是什么
has as few nodes as possible but height 4?
有尽可能少的节点，但高度为4？
If this guy has to be at height 4,
如果这个家伙必须身高4，
then it has to have a child at height 3, at least one child.
那么它必须有一个3岁高的孩子，至少一个孩子。
Otherwise, it's not going to be height 4.
否则，它将不会达到高度4。
Now, I need to build something here that has height 3.
现在，我需要在此处构建高度为3的东西。
What should I build?
我应该建造什么？
The best AVL tree that I know that has height 3, right?
我知道的最好的AVL树的高度为3，对吗？
I have to get to height 3 using as few nodes as possible,
我必须使用尽可能少的节点来达到高度3，
so I'm going to use this guy because it has as few nodes as
所以我要使用这个人，因为它的节点数尽可能少
possible and it has height 3.
可能的，它的高度为3。
So this covers my right side.
所以这涵盖了我的右边。
Now, for my left side, what am I going to use here?
现在，对于我的左侧，我将在这里使用什么？
Another AVL tree that has as few nodes as possible, right?
另一个具有尽可能少的节点的AVL树，对不对？
So I'm definitely keeping that.
所以我绝对会保留。
But what's going to be the height of that?
但是，高度将是什么？
AUDIENCE: So we want the difference to be less than
听众：所以我们希望差异小于
or equal to 1?
或等于1？
PROFESSOR: Yeah.
教授：是的。
Otherwise, it's not an AVL.
否则，它不是AVL。
AUDIENCE: So it would be of height 4.
听众：高度为4。
PROFESSOR: So I know for sure that this guy has height 4.
教授：所以我确定这家伙的身高是4。
The difference has to be plus, minus 1.
差值必须为正负1。
AUDIENCE: So it would be 2.
听众：所以应该是2。
PROFESSOR: 2, 3, 4.
教授：2、3、4
I know for sure I don't want it to be 4,
我知道我不希望它是4
and now I have to choose between 2 and 3.
现在我必须在2到3之间进行选择
A tree of height 2 will have fewer nodes
高度为2的树的节点更少
than a tree of height 3, so that's
比一棵高3的树，所以
why we're doing it this way.
为什么我们要这样做
So to build a tree of height 4, build a tree of height 3,
因此，要建造一棵高4的树，建造一棵高3的树，
build a tree of height 2, connect them together.
建一棵高2的树，将它们连接在一起。
That's how we get to this, and then this.
这就是我们要达到的目标，然后是目标。
Cool.
凉。
Do people remember how to do insertions and deletions
人们是否记得如何进行插入和删除
in a regular binary tree?
在常规的二叉树中？
Yes?
是？
How do I insert 6.5 here in this one?
我要如何在这里插入6.5？
AUDIENCE: You take 6.5, you're like, oh, it's greater than 4,
听众：您拿6.5，就像，哦，大于4，
then you move to 5.
然后转到5。
Then you're like, oh, it's greater than 5.
然后，您就像哦，大于5。
Go to 6.
转到6。
Oh, it's less than 6, and then it goes to the left of 6.
哦，它小于6，然后到6的左边。
I mean-- sorry.
我的意思是-抱歉。
I meant left of 7.
我的意思是离开7。
PROFESSOR: OK.
教授：好的。
So it's bigger than--
因此，它比-
AUDIENCE: Testing you all, guys.
观众：大家都在测试。
Oh yeah.
哦耶。
6.5 is bigger than 6, so then it goes to the left of 7
6.5大于6，因此它位于7的左侧
because it's less than 7.
因为小于7
PROFESSOR: I thought I had my example wrong for a second.
教授：我以为我的例子错了一秒钟。
AUDIENCE: I'm just tired.
听众：我很累。
PROFESSOR: Me too, so don't scare me.
教授：我也是，所以不要吓我。
All right.
好吧。
So suppose we have heights stored in the nodes here,
因此，假设我们在此处的节点中存储了高度，
because we want to do that for AVLs.
因为我们要为AVL做到这一点。
We'll figure out why in a bit.
我们稍后会找出原因。
The height of this guy used to be 0, 1, 2, 3, right?
这个家伙的身高曾经是0、1、2、3，对吧？
0, 1, 2, 3.
0、1、2、3。
What happened when I added this node?
添加此节点时发生了什么？
AUDIENCE: You added 1 to everything [INAUDIBLE].
听众：您对所有[听不清]加了1。
PROFESSOR: Yeah.
教授：是的。
So I went down on my insertion path
所以我沿着插入路径走了
to find out where to insert a node, and then I added it.
找出要插入节点的位置，然后将其添加。
I just chose my case conveniently,
我只是方便地选择了我的箱子，
but in some cases, all the heights
但在某些情况下，所有高度
of the nodes on that path have changed.
该路径上的节点数已更改。
So in an AVL, after we insert, we
因此，在AVL中，插入后
have to make sure that the height
必须确保高度
of every node on the path is updated.
路径上每个节点的更新。
Does this make sense?
这有意义吗？
So the heights will be 1, 2, 3, 4.
因此，高度将为1、2、3、4。
So the way we implemented the AVLs is
因此，我们实施AVL的方式是
that we do regular insertions and deletions,
我们会定期进行插入和删除操作，
and then at the end, we say, well it used to be an AVL.
最后，我们说它曾经是AVL。
Now we added or removed the node,
现在我们添加或删除了该节点，
so it might be a slightly unbalanced AVL,
因此它可能是略微不平衡的AVL，
which means it's not an AVL.
这意味着它不是AVL。
And we have the rebalance procedure.
我们有重新平衡程序。
So if you look at on the second page of the code,
因此，如果您查看代码的第二页，
insert and delete are really tiny, lines 20 to 22
插入和删除的确很小，第20至22行
and 24 to 28.
和24至28。
And they're really tiny because they call the old code
而且它们真的很小，因为它们调用了旧代码
and then they call Rebalance.
然后他们称重新平衡。
So all the magic in an AVL is in Rebalance.
因此，AVL中的所有魔力都在重新平衡中。
The first thing that Rebalance does, if you see,
如果您看到，Rebalance要做的第一件事就是，
it has a while loop there, and the first thing that it does
它在那里有一个while循环，它做的第一件事
in the while loop is it updates the height, and this is why.
在while循环中它会更新高度，这就是原因。
The height might have changed after the insert,
插入后，高度可能已更改，
so any decision based on the old height is bad.
因此任何基于旧高度的决定都是不好的。
That's why we have that there.
这就是为什么我们在那里。
Make sense so far?
到目前为止有意义吗？
So if you look at rebalance, don't try to understand it
因此，如果您考虑重新平衡，请不要试图理解它
quite yet, but what it does is it
还没有，但是它的作用是
calls Rotate Left and Rotate Right.
调用“向左旋转”和“向右旋转”。
Well, Left Rotate, Right Rotate.
好吧，向左旋转，向右旋转。
All the magic is in Rebalance, and the tools that it uses
所有的魔力都在重新平衡中，以及它所使用的工具
are Left Rotate and Right Rotate.
是“向左旋转”和“向右旋转”。
Now, I'm going to show you what a rotation is supposed
现在，我将向您展示应该进行的轮换
to do in-- and the children of these nodes are a, b, c, d.
要做-这些节点的子节点是a，b，c，d。
Also, this node is hanging off of something here, e.
同样，此节点在这里悬挂着某些东西。
If I want to do a Right Rotate here,
如果我想在这里进行右旋转，
so if I want to rotate the tree like this, then after rotating,
所以如果我想像这样旋转树，那么旋转后
it's going to look like this.
它看起来像这样。
So notice that c got moved from B to A, but it got
所以请注意c从B移到A，但是
moved in such a way that the whole thing is still a BST.
整个过程仍然是BST。
These guys show up in the same order as children,
这些人的出现顺序与孩子相同，
and these guys show up in the same order,
这些家伙以相同的顺序出现，
so search will still work.
因此搜索仍然有效。
This is how it's supposed to look like as a picture.
这就是它看起来像图片的样子。
Let's try to write the pseudocode for achieving this.
让我们尝试编写用于实现此目的的伪代码。
AUDIENCE: First, you identify the parent node.
听众：首先，您确定父节点。
Step one.
第一步。
PROFESSOR: Well, let's say we have it.
教授：好吧，我们可以拥有它。
AUDIENCE: I mean from B. You say, A is my parent.
听众：我的意思是从B。你说，A是我的父母。
That's now going to become my right child.
现在这将成为我的正确孩子。
PROFESSOR: OK.
教授：好的。
So what do you want to change?
那你想改变什么？
By the way, this whole thing has to happen in constant time,
顺便说一句，这整个事情必须在恒定的时间内发生，
so we're not allowed to go anywhere inside here, here,
所以我们不允许在这里，这里，
here, or here.
在这里或这里。
We're allowed to change these links,
我们可以更改这些链接，
but if you go inside and try to do
但是如果你进去尝试
more complicated restructuring, that's
更复杂的重组，那就是
going to block the running time.
会阻塞运行时间。
We're only allowed to change the links
我们只允许更改链接
that you see on the board.
您在黑板上看到的。
AUDIENCE: I know in the BST, not BST node but BST, the delete,
听众：我知道在BST中，不是BST节点，而是BST，删除，
if you're deleting the root, they make up the pseudoroot.
如果要删除根，则它们将构成伪根。
PROFESSOR: Let's not worry about it.
教授：我们不用担心。
So Delete already did that magic for you, right?
所以Delete已经为您做到了，对吗？
So the pseudoroot would be here, so this node has a root.
因此伪根将在此处，因此该节点具有根。
We're happy.
很高兴。
AUDIENCE: That's not what I'm talking about.
听众：我不是在说这个。
I'm saying that you could do the same with B because you're
我是说你可以对B做同样的事情，因为你
going to have to break a link with lowercase c onto B
将不得不断开小写字母c到B的链接
in order to flip it.
为了翻转它。
So I'm saying you could have a placer, some sort of place
所以我说你可以有一个放置器
to put it so you don't lose it.
放它，这样您就不会丢失它。
PROFESSOR: OK.
教授：好的。
Let's see if we do that.
让我们看看我们是否这样做。
AUDIENCE: The new right child of B will be A,
听众：B的新右子将是A，
and the new left child of A will be C, and the new parent of c
A的新左子将是C，c的新父
is A.
是A。
PROFESSOR: OK, let's move slower.
教授：好的，我们走慢一些。
I have to write them down.
我要写下来
So the new right child of B is?
那么B的新右子是？
AUDIENCE: Is A. Also, you probably
听众：是A。另外，你可能
should do temp variables to store them.
应该做临时变量来存储它们。
AUDIENCE: I don't think you have to.
听众：我认为你不必这样做。
You can just swap the one connection and swap the other.
您可以交换一个连接而交换另一个连接。
PROFESSOR: Let's do it without worrying about temps,
教授：我们不用担心临时工，
and then we can figure out temps later.
然后我们可以找出临时的
So B's right becomes A. So it's going to be like this.
这样B的权利就变成了A。所以它将像这样。
Let me erase this confusing error.
让我消除这个令人困惑的错误。
AUDIENCE: And A's left child is c.
听众：A的左孩子是c。
PROFESSOR: A's left child is c.
教授：A的左孩子是c。
OK.
好。
AUDIENCE: C's parent is A.
听众：C的父母是A。
PROFESSOR: C's parent is A. OK, very good.
教授：C的父母是A。好的，很好。
So I changed the child, then I changed the parent
所以我改变了孩子，然后我改变了父母
so that they would match up.
这样他们才能配对。
So if B's right is A, then what should I do with--
因此，如果B的权利是A，那我该怎么做-
AUDIENCE: A's parent is B.
听众：A的父母是B。
PROFESSOR: Always do them in pairs
教授：总是成对做
so you don't lose track of them.
这样您就不会失去对它们的了解。
And?
和？
AUDIENCE: B's parent is e and e's subchild is B.
听众：B的父母是e，e的子孩子是B。
PROFESSOR: Sorry.
教授：对不起。
B's parent is e, right?
B的父母是e，对吗？
AUDIENCE: Yeah.
听众：是的。
PROFESSOR: So B's parent is e, and--
教授：那么B的父母是e，并且-
AUDIENCE: e's left.
听众：e离开了。
PROFESSOR: Child is--
教授：孩子是-
AUDIENCE: B.
听众：B.
PROFESSOR: Because I drew it like this, right?
教授：因为我是这样画的，对吗？
But if I drew it like this?
但是如果我这样画的话？
AUDIENCE: e's--
听众：e是
PROFESSOR: It would have to be the right child,
教授：那一定是合适的孩子，
so we have to look at both cases.
所以我们必须看两种情况。
AUDIENCE: If B is greater than e,
听众：如果B大于e，
then it would be right child, and if B is less than e,
那将是正确的孩子，如果B小于e，
it would be left child.
那将是孩子。
PROFESSOR: OK.
教授：好的。
So if B is greater than e, then e's right is B.
因此，如果B大于e，那么e的权利就是B。
Otherwise, e's left is B, right?
否则，e的左边是B，对吗？
Now, suppose comparisons are expensive
现在，假设比较昂贵
and they don't want to do a comparison to find this out.
他们不想进行比较以找出答案。
I want to play with the tree instead.
我想和树一起玩。
What do I do?
我该怎么办？
AUDIENCE: Can you see which one A was before that?
听众：你能看到之前的那个A吗？
PROFESSOR: Yep.
教授：是的。
AUDIENCE: If A used to be the right child,
听众：如果A曾经是合适的孩子，
now B is the right child.
现在B是合适的孩子。
PROFESSOR: Yeah.
教授：是的。
I haven't changed the child yet, so I can do that.
我还没有改变孩子，所以我可以做到。
AUDIENCE: That's still a comparison though, right?
听众：但这仍然是一个比较，对吗？
PROFESSOR: But now I'm doing a pointer comparison and not
教授：但是现在我在做指针比较，而不是
a key comparison.
关键比较。
AUDIENCE: If e.r is A, then--
听众：如果er是A，则-
PROFESSOR: If e.right is A, then it becomes B. Otherwise.
教授：如果e.right是A，则它成为B。否则。
OK, this looks good.
好，看起来不错
So there's the issue of temp variables
因此存在临时变量的问题
and assigning these in the right order
并按正确的顺序分配它们
so you don't have too many temp variables and too
所以你没有太多的临时变量
many lines of code, and the Python code in the handout
多行代码，以及讲义中的Python代码
takes care of that.
照顾那个。
But this is the logic that you want.
但这是您想要的逻辑。
So if you have to write it from scratch,
因此，如果您必须从头开始编写，
you don't have to memorize that.
您不必记住这一点。
Remember that you want to get from here to here,
请记住，您想从这里到达这里，
and do exactly the thought process that we have here.
并精确地进行我们在这里的思考过程。
What if I want to do a left rotation instead
如果我想做左旋转怎么办
of a right rotation?
右旋转？
AUDIENCE: You just have to change the r's to l's.
听众：您只需要将r更改为l。
PROFESSOR: Very good.
教授：非常好。
Copy, paste.
复制粘贴。
Swap l's and r's and we're done.
交换l和r，我们就完成了。
Why do we need rotations?
为什么我们需要轮换？
AUDIENCE: To rebalance stuff.
听众：重新平衡事物。
PROFESSOR: To rebalance stuff.
教授：重新平衡东西。
OK.
好。
Why do we rebalance stuff?
为什么我们要重新平衡东西？
AUDIENCE: Because you don't want your code
听众：因为你不想要你的代码
to crash when you add nodes that are sequentially larger,
当添加顺序更大的节点时崩溃，
and then you try to find something, and then it crashes.
然后尝试找到某些东西，然后崩溃。
PROFESSOR: OK.
教授：好的。
Why would it crash?
为什么会崩溃？
AUDIENCE: Because the recursion depth
听众：因为递归深度
is exceeded because you're going down
被超越，因为你要下去
the line trying to find something,
线试图找到一些东西，
and you go down too far.
而且你走得太远了。
PROFESSOR: OK.
教授：好的。
So pretending we don't have a recursion depth issue,
因此，假装我们没有递归深度问题，
then it's going to be slow.
那就慢了
So you start from a nice AVL, and if you don't rebalance,
因此，您从一个不错的AVL开始，如果您不重新平衡，
you get to a BST that's slow, slow, slow,
您会遇到缓慢，缓慢，缓慢的BST，
and then you'll fail our tests and still get a 0.
然后您将无法通过我们的测试，但仍然得到0。
Yes?
是？
AUDIENCE: But if you just had a carrot-like tree,
观众：但是如果你有一棵胡萝卜状的树，
or if you added, for instance, 4, and then you added in 5,
或者您添加了例如4，然后添加了5
and then you added in 3, and then you added in 6,
然后添加3，然后添加6，
and then you added in 2, you'd just get a carrot.
然后添加2，就可以得到胡萝卜。
So then I feel like AVL wouldn't cover that case.
因此，我觉得AVL无法解决这种情况。
PROFESSOR: Let's do them in sequence.
教授：让我们按顺序进行。
So what are we inserting?
那么我们要插入什么？
So you said 4.
所以你说4。
AUDIENCE: So you start with 4, and then you insert 5,
听众：因此，您从4开始，然后插入5，
then you insert 3.
然后插入3。
PROFESSOR: Let's see.
教授：让我们看看。
4, 3.
4、3
AUDIENCE: Then you insert 6, then you insert 2,
听众：然后插入6，然后插入2，
then you insert 7, and then 1.
然后输入7，然后输入1。
AUDIENCE: You've got to rotate that.
听众：您必须旋转它。
AUDIENCE: Well, the thing is--
听众：好吧，事情是-
PROFESSOR: Well, is this an AVL?
教授：嗯，这是AVL吗？
PROFESSOR: Well, it's balanced.
教授：好吧，这很均衡。
PROFESSOR: Is it?
教授：是吗？
AUDIENCE: No, it's not.
听众：不，不是。
5 is unhappy.
5不开心。
AUDIENCE: That height of the tree is only one
听众：那棵树的高度只有一
greater than the other height.
大于其他高度。
PROFESSOR: So the height here is 1.
教授：所以这里的高度是1。
What's the height here?
这里的高度是多少？
There's nothing here, so the height is minus 1.
这里什么都没有，所以高度是负1。
AUDIENCE: I mean, but the other side of the tree.
听众：我的意思是，但那棵树的另一边。
PROFESSOR: So if you're looking at this guy,
教授：所以，如果您正在寻找这个人，
things look balanced, but in an AVL,
情况看起来很平衡，但是在AVL中，
this has to hold for every node.
这必须适用于每个节点。
If there's one node where the heights are unbalanced,
如果有一个节点的高度不平衡，
the whole thing is unbalanced.
整个事情是不平衡的。
Otherwise, the construction that we did before
否则，我们之前所做的构造
wouldn't make sense.
没道理
AUDIENCE: It's all [INAUDIBLE] within the [INAUDIBLE].
听众：[音频不清晰]中的所有[音频不清晰]。
PROFESSOR: Yep.
教授：是的。
So now that we're going to look at rebalancing, which
所以现在我们要考虑重新平衡，
is the magic behind AVLs, we have
是AVL背后的魔力，我们有
to make sure that after we start with something that's
确保在我们开始时
slightly imbalanced, when we rotate things around,
稍微不平衡，当我们旋转事物时，
we have to make sure that everything gets balanced
我们必须确保一切都平衡
at the end and happy, so that's a good thing to keep in mind.
最后要开心，所以要牢记这是一件好事。
Good.
好。
Any other questions?
还有其他问题吗？
AUDIENCE: Is it obvious that you can
听众：很明显，你可以
put any number of nodes in an AVL tree?
在AVL树中放置任意数量的节点？
PROFESSOR: Point any number of nodes?
教授：指向多少个节点？
AUDIENCE: Yeah.
听众：是的。
It's obvious that you can do one node, or two nodes or three
很明显，您可以做一个节点，或者两个或三个节点
nodes, but is it true that for any number of nodes,
节点，但是对于任何数量的节点，
you can arrange into an AVL tree?
你可以安排成AVL树吗？
Does that make sense?
那有意义吗？
PROFESSOR: Yeah.
教授：是的。
So if you want to have any number of nodes,
因此，如果您想拥有任意数量的节点，
you call Insert, AVL Insert, and then you'll get an AVL.
依次调用“插入”，“ AVL插入”，然后您将获得一个AVL。
AUDIENCE: Right.
听众：对。
But what I'm trying to say is, is it
但是我想说的是
possible to construct an AVL tree out of 13 nodes?
可以从13个节点中构建AVL树？
PROFESSOR: Sure.
教授：当然可以。
AUDIENCE: Or 17 nodes?
听众：还是17个节点？
AUDIENCE: Is there a limit for where that property will not
听众：该财产不会受到限制的地方
fit?
适合？
AUDIENCE: Right.
听众：对。
Is there some set of nodes--
是否有一些节点集-
PROFESSOR: I like this question.
教授：我喜欢这个问题。
I like this question.
我喜欢这个问题。
So what would be the perfect binary search tree?
那么什么是完美的二叉搜索树？
AUDIENCE: An element of log N height.
听众：高度为N的元素。
PROFESSOR: An element of log N height
教授：高度为N的元素
and the complete tree, so something that looks like this.
和完整的树，看起来像这样
Where did we see this thing before?
我们以前在哪里看过这个东西？
AUDIENCE: In the heap.
听众：在堆里​​。
PROFESSOR: All right.
教授：好的。
So a heap looks exactly like this,
所以堆看起来像这样
except the values inside don't fulfill the BST requirement.
除了其中的值不满足BST要求。
Otherwise, we'd know how to build perfect BSTs.
否则，我们将知道如何构建完善的BST。
It so happens that we don't.
碰巧我们没有。
But is this an AVL?
但这是AVL吗？
AUDIENCE: Yes.
听众：是的。
AUDIENCE: That example or in general?
听众：那个例子还是一般来说？
PROFESSOR: Let's start with that example.
教授：让我们从该示例开始。
Is this an AVL?
这是AVL吗？
AUDIENCE: No.
听众：不。
The node just to the left of the root--
根节点左侧的节点-
PROFESSOR: This guy?
教授：这个家伙？
AUDIENCE: No.
听众：不。
That one's of height two, so it has height one.
这个人的身高是2，所以它的身高是1。
PROFESSOR: This is beautiful.
教授：这很漂亮。
This is as good as it could get.
这是可以得到的。
This is an optimal binary search tree.
这是最佳的二叉搜索树。
This is perfect.
太棒了。
It better match the definition of AVL,
它更符合AVL的定义，
because otherwise, it would mean AVL doesn't like perfect trees.
因为否则，这将意味着AVL不喜欢完美的树木。
So the good news is that any complete tree
好消息是，任何一棵完整的树
is going to be an AVL because everything
将成为一个AVL，因为一切
is perfectly balanced or almost perfectly balanced.
完全平衡或几乎完全平衡。
The only thing that's not complete is the last level.
唯一不完整的是最后一个级别。
So all the paths from the roots to the last level
因此，从根到最后一层的所有路径
are either height log N or height log N minus 1.
是高度对数N或高度对数N减去1。
So wherever you do the height comparison,
因此，无论您在哪里进行高度比较，
you're going to get a difference of 1,
您将得到1，
and we can keep adding nodes to this.
并且我们可以继续向其添加节点。
This is how I'd build a BST of as many nodes as we want.
这就是我要构建尽可能多的节点的BST的方式。
AUDIENCE: I have a question.
听众：我有一个问题。
For the fixed heights, why we try to minimize the nodes?
对于固定的高度，为什么我们尝试最小化节点？
Wouldn't a better way to build a more efficient tree
没有更好的方法来构建更有效率的树
is to try to minimize the height?
是要尽量减小高度？
So instead of adding nodes up, just fill in the tree?
因此，无需添加节点，只需填充树即可？
PROFESSOR: Very good.
教授：非常好。
So you're thinking of how to build an efficient tree, how
因此，您正在考虑如何构建高效的树，
to build a good tree.
建一棵好树。
Here, I'm trying to prove the property
在这里，我试图证明财产
about the maximum height of a tree.
大约一棵树的最大高度。
So here I'm playing devil's advocate.
所以我在这里扮演恶魔的拥护者。
I'm thinking, what is the worst case for AVLs?
我在想，AVL最坏的情况是什么？
How do I make AVLs look as bad as possible?
如何使AVL看起来越差越好？
That's why I started this way.
这就是为什么我以这种方式开始。
So usually, we're the good guy coding,
通常，我们是编码的好人，
but after you're done coding and you
但是在完成编码之后
know how your algorithm runs, if you want to have peace of mind
如果您想放心，知道算法的运行方式
and go to sleep well and get full points afterwards,
睡个好觉，然后得到满分，
it sometimes helps to think as devil's advocate.
有时有助于将其视为恶魔的拥护者。
How would I break this algorithm?
我将如何打破这种算法？
What's the worst thing that I could do to it?
我能做的最坏的事情是什么？
And if you can find something that breaks it,
如果您能找到破坏它的东西，
well, you probably know how to fix it.
好吧，您可能知道如何解决它。
If not, you can sleep well at night
如果没有的话，晚上可以睡个好觉
and know that your algorithm is sound.
并且知道您的算法是正确的。
AUDIENCE: In that example on the board, where we said
观众：在董事会的那个例子中，我们说
the height of the tree on the left side was h minus 1,
左侧树的高度为h减去1，
and then the other side had the h minus 2.
然后另一边的h减2。
For that h minus 2 tree, every node in that
对于那个h减去2树，那个树中的每个节点
has to be h minus 2 height, every leaf.
每片叶子必须为h减去2高度。
Is that what we're saying?
这就是我们要说的吗？
Otherwise, it falls apart because there would be one
否则，它会崩溃，因为会有一个
that's--
那是 -
PROFESSOR: So we're saying that the root of this tree
教授：所以我们说这棵树的根
has to be h minus 2.
必须为h减2。
And the way we do this is we copy this guy over,
我们这样做的方法是将这个人复制过来，
so this guy's lopsided, too.
所以这家伙也变了
So it's not every path to the bottom, just one path.
因此，并不是每条到达底部的路径，而是一条路径。
AUDIENCE: OK.
听众：好的。
So it could be an incomplete.
因此可能是不完整的。
PROFESSOR: Yep.
教授：是的。
In that case, is that balanced?
在那种情况下，那是平衡的吗？
PROFESSOR: So this was an AVL of height 2, right?
教授：所以这是2号高度的AVL，对吗？
If I stick it here, it's still going to be an AVL of height 2.
如果我把它贴在这里，它仍将是高度2的AVL。
AUDIENCE: Right.
听众：对。
PROFESSOR: This thing will have height 2.
教授：这东西的高度为2。
This thing will have height 3.
这东西的高度为3。
AUDIENCE: OK.
听众：好的。
So it's not everything on the same level,
因此，并非所有事物都处于同一水平，
necessarily, that needs to be of the same height.
当然，它必须具有相同的高度。
It's only the children.
只有孩子们。
PROFESSOR: Yep.
教授：是的。
So the two children, so two nodes on the same level,
所以两个孩子，所以两个节点在同一水平上
might have their heights differ by one, but not more than one.
高度可能相差一，但不能超过一。
If they could differ by more than one,
如果它们相差一个以上，
you could have a link list.
您可能会有一个链接列表。
Because they differ by one, then it's sort of sane.
因为它们相差一个，所以有点理智。
It's almost balanced.
它几乎是平衡的。
Good.
好。
I like the questions.
我喜欢这些问题。
It means you guys are thinking.
这意味着你们正在思考。
I really like it.
我很喜欢。
Yeah?
是啊
AUDIENCE: If they differ by one.
听众：如果两者相差一。
So you have an ideal tree up there,
所以你在那里有一棵理想的树，
and then you have the worst case possible.
然后您可能会遇到最坏的情况。
That wouldn't affect performance at all, right,
完全不会影响性能，对，
if you have the worst case?
如果你有最坏的情况？
PROFESSOR: So what we know what performance is we
教授：所以我们知道我们的表现是什么
have this guarantee.
有这个保证。
It's at worst a constant times log n.
最坏的情况是常数n为log。
This is constant times log n.
这是常数乘以log n。
The constant happens to be 1.
该常数恰好是1。
This is a constant times log n.
这是常数乘以log n。
The constant happens to be something bigger than 1.
该常数恰好大于1。
I think it's somewhere between 2 and 3.
我认为它介于2到3之间。
AUDIENCE: That just varies by the constant.
听众：只是随常数而变化。
PROFESSOR: Yeah.
教授：是的。
And since we only care about asymptotics in this class,
而且由于我们只关心此类的无症状性，
we're happy.
很高兴。
But we don't know how to build this.
但是我们不知道该如何构建。
This is just something pretty that we draw on a board,
这只是我们在板上画的东西，
but we don't have an algorithm that efficiency builds
但是我们没有一个可以提高效率的算法
this out of a random series of insertions and deletions.
这是一系列随机的插入和删除操作。
I hope we don't.
我希望我们不要。
Otherwise, I look bad.
否则，我看起来不好。
What do I want to delete?
我要删除什么？
AUDIENCE: Instead of a binary search
听众：而不是二进制搜索
tree as the base of the AVL, if you
如果树是AVL的基础
wanted to have four children per node,
希望每个节点有四个孩子，
would this change that much except you'd
除了你会改变很多吗
just have twice as many variables?
仅有两倍的变量？
PROFESSOR: That's a good exam question.
教授：这是一个很好的考试问题。
So it turns out that there's this tree called
结果发现这棵树叫做
a B tree, which has 1,000 or more nodes.
B树，具有1,000或更多的节点。
AUDIENCE: B tree?
听众：B树？
Doesn't that stand for binary?
那不是二进制吗？
PROFESSOR: No.
教授：不。
It's B. Just B. That's used for databases on disk.
是B。只是B。用于磁盘上的数据库。
So there, you want to make the height as small as possible,
因此，您要使高度尽可能小，
because every time you get a node, you do a disk access,
因为每次获得节点时，您都​​需要进行磁盘访问，
and that's expensive.
那很贵。
But once you do a disk access, the nodes
但是一旦完成磁盘访问，节点
can be as big as you want.
可以随心所欲。
You can read a few bytes off the disk at roughly the same cost
您可以以大致相同的成本从磁盘读取几个字节
as you can read a megabyte, so you're better off
因为您可以读取1兆字节，所以最好
reading a megabyte.
读取一个兆字节。
I might be exaggerating a bit, but for a few kilobytes,
我可能会有点夸张，但是对于几千字节，
that's true.
确实如此。
So B trees have thousands of children,
所以B树有成千上万的孩子，
and they keep them sorted.
他们保持排序。
It's sort of like that, but the fan out is huge.
有点像，但是扇出的扇子很大。
And it turns out everything is still log n
事实证明一切仍然在记录
as long as the number of children you have is constant.
只要您的孩子数量是恒定的。
AUDIENCE: But for this rotation thing, though.
听众：但是，对于这种轮换来说。
PROFESSOR: Oh god, no.
教授：哦，天哪。
We don't have to rotate.
我们不必旋转。
It gets a lot more complicated.
它变得更加复杂。
We haven't gotten to rebalancing yet, right?
我们还没有重新平衡，对吗？
Wait until you see how rebalancing looks like
等到看到重新平衡的样子
with two children, and then imagine
有两个孩子，然后想象
trying to figure out the cases for 1,000 children.
试图找出1000名儿童的情况。
That's not sane.
那不是理智
In B trees, they use something else
在B树中，他们使用其他东西
to make them balance the right way.
使他们平衡正确的方法。
And of course, they're harder than this.
当然，它们比这更难。
So let me try to get through rebalancing somewhat quickly.
因此，让我尝试快速完成重新平衡。
This is where I forget what I need to do.
这是我忘记要做的事情的地方。
Rebalancing.
重新平衡。
So suppose we call Rebalance on this guy,
因此，假设我们称这个人为Rebalance，
and we know that the nodes here have heights k minus 1,
我们知道这里的节点的高度为k减去1
this is k minus 1 or k, and this is k,
这是k减去1或k，这是k，
and I want to call Rebalance here.
我想在这里打电话给Rebalance。
Let's first figure out if it's an AVL tree
首先让我们弄清楚它是否是AVL树
or if there's something wrong with it.
或者它有什么问题。
What's the height here?
这里的高度是多少？
AUDIENCE: k plus 1.
听众：k加1。
PROFESSOR: So no matter what the height is here,
教授：所以无论这里的高度
the height here has to be k plus 1.
这里的高度必须是k加1。
What's the height here?
这里的高度是多少？
AUDIENCE: k plus 2.
听众：k加2。
PROFESSOR: OK.
教授：好的。
What else can you tell me about this node?
关于这个节点，您还能告诉我什么？
If I call Check RI on it, it's going
如果我打电话给Check RI，它会
to crash because the rep invariant for AVLs
崩溃，因为AVL的rep不变
does not hold here.
在这里不举行。
This child at the top of this tree
这个孩子在这棵树的顶端
will have height k minus 1.
高度k减去1。
This will have height k plus 1.
这将具有高度k加1。
The difference is more than 1.
差异大于1。
Not good.
不好。
So this is unhappy.
所以这很不高兴。
How do we fix the situation?
我们如何解决这种情况？
AUDIENCE: Rotate left around k plus 1.
观众：向左旋转k加1。
PROFESSOR: All right.
教授：好的。
So it better be a rotation, because we spent so much
最好是轮换，因为我们花了很多钱
figuring out how to rotate.
弄清楚如何旋转。
Let's see what happens if we rotate this way,
让我们看看如果我们这样旋转，会发生什么，
and the way to keep track of this
以及保持追踪的方式
is I'm going to label my nodes.
我要标记我的节点。
B, A, left child of A has height k minus 1.
B，A，A的左孩子的身高k减去1。
This guy is k minus 1.
这个人是k减1。
So what's the height of A now?
那么，A的高度是多少？
AUDIENCE: k.
观众：k。
Oh wait, that's not a node.
哦，等等，这不是节点。
Just k minus 1 or k.
只需k减去1或k。
PROFESSOR: So this is a tree of height k minus 1.
教授：这是一棵树，高k减1。
This is a height of tree k minus 1 or k.
这是树的高度k减去1或k。
The height of this guy is?
这个家伙的身高是多少？
AUDIENCE: k.
观众：k。
AUDIENCE: k plus 1.
听众：k加1。
PROFESSOR: Or k plus 1.
教授：或k加1。
The height of this guy is definitely k.
这个家伙的身高绝对是k。
The height of this guys is k or k plus 1.
这些人的身高是k或k加1。
Is that an AVL?
那是AVL吗？
Is it happy now?
现在幸福吗？
So this is the easy kind of rebalancing, one rotation
所以这是一种简单的重新平衡操作
and you're done.
到此为止。
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE] the difference between k
听众：[听不清] k之间的差
minus 1 and k minus 1 over k?
减1和k减去k减1？
PROFESSOR: It's not k minus 1 over k.
教授：不是k减去k减去1。
It's either k minus 1 or k.
它是k减去1或k。
Bad notation.
错误的符号。
Thank you for the question.
感谢你的提问。
You saved everyone from confusion.
您使所有人免于混乱。
No, there's no fractional heights.
不，没有分数高度。
Anything else?
还要别的吗？
Thank you.
谢谢。
That was good.
那很好。
All right.
好吧。
So this is easy, right?
所以这很容易，对吗？
This is the easy rotation.
这是容易的旋转。
Let's do the hard one now.
现在让我们努力吧。
What's the height here?
这里的高度是多少？
AUDIENCE: k plus 1.
听众：k加1。
PROFESSOR: What's the height here?
教授：这里的高度是多少？
AUDIENCE: Plus 2.
观众：加2。
PROFESSOR: AVL, not AVL?
教授：AVL，不是AVL？
AUDIENCE: No.
听众：不。
PROFESSOR: k minus 1 on the left child,
教授：左侧孩子的k减去1，
k plus 1 on the right child.
k在正确的孩子上加1。
The difference is more than one.
差异不止一个。
Not an AVL.
不是AVL。
How do we fix this?
我们该如何解决？
AUDIENCE: Make a right rotation [INAUDIBLE].
听众：右旋转[听不清]。
PROFESSOR: Sorry?
教授：对不起？
AUDIENCE: Make a right rotation on k first.
听众：首先在k上右旋转。
PROFESSOR: So make a right rotation where?
教授：那么，在哪里进行正确的轮换？
AUDIENCE: On k [INAUDIBLE] plus 1.
受众群体：在k [听不清]上加1。
PROFESSOR: Let me break this up so we
教授：让我分解一下，所以我们
could see how that would work out.
可以看到如何解决。
So these two are k minus 1 and k minus 1,
所以这两个是k减1和k减1
and these nodes are A, B, and C. So you're
这些节点是A，B和C。
saying do a right rotation here, right?
说在这里右转吧？
Let's see what that gets us to.
让我们看看能带给我们什么。
So A is the same, and then here I'm
所以A是一样的，然后我在这里
going to have C instead of B, and B. The right child of B
将拥有C而不是B和B。B的正确子代
is the same as it was before.
和以前一样。
The left child of B is k minus 1.
B的左孩子是k减1。
Then the left child of C is another k minus 1,
那么C的左孩子又是k减1，
and this guy is k minus 1.
这个家伙是k减1。
OK, what's the height at B now?
好，现在B的高度是多少？
AUDIENCE: k.
观众：k。
PROFESSOR: OK.
教授：好的。
What's the height here?
这里的高度是多少？
AUDIENCE: k plus 1.
听众：k加1。
PROFESSOR: And the height here?
教授：这里的高度是多少？
AUDIENCE: k plus 2.
听众：k加2。
PROFESSOR: Is this an AVL?
教授：这是AVL吗？
So we're not done, but what's the good news about this?
因此，我们还没有完成，但是这有什么好消息呢？
AUDIENCE: Now you can rotate it left around C.
听众：现在您可以将其向C左旋转。
PROFESSOR: Yep.
教授：是的。
Exactly.
究竟。
That is this, and we know how to fix this in one step.
就是这样，我们知道如何一步解决。
You said exactly the right thing.
你说的完全正确。
This is exactly what we do.
这正是我们所做的。
First, rotate here so that we get to that,
首先，在这里旋转，以便我们可以做到这一点，
and then we're in the happy case.
然后我们就很高兴了。
So intuitively, the difference between the happy case
如此直观地讲，幸福案例之间的区别
and the harder case that's going to be happy eventually
最终将变得更加艰难的情况
is where the heavy path is, so where
是重路在哪里，所以在哪里
you have the bigger height.
你的身高更大。
In this case, k plus 2, k plus 1, k.
在这种情况下，k加2，k加1，k。
So the heavy path is this thing here.
所以这条路很重。
It's a straight line.
这是一条直线。
Because of that, we can rotate here and then
因此，我们可以在这里旋转
redistribute the weights uniformly.
重新分配权重。
In this case, the heavy path is this.
在这种情况下，繁重的道路就是这样。
It's a zigzag, so one rotation won't fix it.
这是锯齿形的，因此旋转一圈将无法解决。
Instead, we do one rotation here so
相反，我们在这里旋转一圈
that we make the weights be distributed
我们使权重分布
in a straight line, and then one rotation here,
在一条直线上，然后在这里旋转一圈，
which makes everything look good.
这使一切看起来都不错。
Yes?
是？
AUDIENCE: So that's just a general pattern.
听众：这只是一般模式。
And you redistribute [INAUDIBLE]?
然后您重新分配[音频不清晰]？
PROFESSOR: So the first thing we do is say you're at a node
教授：所以我们要做的第一件事就是说你在一个节点上
and you need to rebalance.
您需要重新平衡。
First thing, you check the heights
首先，您检查身高
and see if it's already balanced.
看看它是否已经平衡。
If it's not balanced, suppose your heavier node
如果不平衡，请假设您的节点较重
is on the right.
在右边。
Then you go and see if the right child is heavier
然后你去看看合适的孩子是否较重
or the left child is heavier.
或左孩子较重。
So you see if the height distribution is a straight line
所以你看高度分布是否是一条直线
or is exact, and then you decide whether you're
或确切，然后您决定是否
going to do one rotation or two rotations.
将要旋转一圈或两圈。
So this is all nice and good except for one thing.
因此，除了一件事情之外，一切都很好。
The heights keep changing here, and we're
高度在这里不断变化，我们
storing the heights in each node.
在每个节点中存储高度。
So if we're doing all this rotating
因此，如果我们要进行所有这些旋转
without updating the heights, then we're
没有更新高度，那么我们
going to have something that looks like an AVL
会有看起来像AVL的东西
but doesn't keep track of the heights anymore,
但不再追踪高度
so eventually, we're going to make bad decisions.
所以最终，我们将做出错误的决定。
So we need to update the heights.
因此，我们需要更新高度。
Where do we update the heights?
我们在哪里更新高度？
You can look at the code and cheat
你可以看一下代码并作弊
or you can try to think and tell me the answer, either way.
或者您可以尝试以任何一种方式思考并告诉我答案。
So this only does rotates, right?
所以这只会旋转，对吧？
If rotates would be able to update the heights,
如果旋转可以更新高度，
everything would be good.
一切都会很好。
I wouldn't have to worry about this.
我不必为此担心。
Pretend I hadn't deleted the original case here,
假装我没有删除原始案例，
which I think was A, B, C, and then some children.
我认为是A，B，C，然后是一些孩子。
What heights changed here?
这里的高度有什么变化？
When I did this rotation, what heights changed?
当我旋转时，什么高度发生变化？
AUDIENCE: B's height changed.
听众：B的身高改变了。
AUDIENCE: B, A, and C is greater than B.
听众：B，A和C大于B。
PROFESSOR: B and potentially A. If I'm not sure,
教授：B，可能还有A。如果不确定，
then I'm going to try to update the height anyway
那我还是要尝试更新高度
to make sure that I have the right height.
确保我的身高合适。
After I do this, I have to update the height on B
完成此操作后，我必须更新B的高度
and update the heights on A. Is this correct?
并更新A的高度。这是正确的吗？
AUDIENCE: And B.
听众：和B。
PROFESSOR: And all the way up.
教授：一直以来。
Let's assume that happens.
假设发生这种情况。
Does this look right?
这看起来正确吗？
AUDIENCE: Don't you also have to update for C?
听众：您是否也不必为C更新？
PROFESSOR: For c.
教授：对于c。
Did I change anything under c?
我在c下更改了什么吗？
AUDIENCE: I think he's talking about capital C.
听众：我认为他是在谈论大写C。
PROFESSOR: Oh, capital C. Yeah, OK.
教授：哦，大写C.是的，好的。
So the children are the same.
所以孩子们是一样的。
They were a and b before, they're a and b afterwards,
他们之前是a和b，之后是a和b，
so I don't have to worry about this guy.
所以我不必担心这个家伙。
The heights here haven't changed,
这里的高度没有改变，
so the height here hasn't changed.
所以这里的高度没有改变。
But you're thinking of a problem,
但是你在想一个问题，
and that is good because there is a problem here.
那很好，因为这里有问题。
AUDIENCE: What if there's a subtree instead of small c?
听众：如果有一个子树而不是小c怎么办？
PROFESSOR: A subtree instead of small c?
教授：是子树而不是小c？
OK, so yeah, this is a subtree.
好的，是的，这是一个子树。
After rotating, this subtree moves over here.
旋转后，此子树将移至此处。
AUDIENCE: Wait.
听众：等等。
You have to update A first, and then update B.
您必须先更新A，然后再更新B。
PROFESSOR: OK.
教授：好的。
So the height starts from the bottom.
因此，高度从底部开始。
The bottom height zero, the next one
底部高度为零，下一个为
up, the next one up, the next one up.
起来，下一个上升，下一个上升。
Keep that in mind.
记住这一点。
Nothing changed below this guy, nothing changed below this guy,
这个家伙下面什么都没改变，这个家伙下面什么都没改变，
nothing changed here, so I don't have to update these.
这里没有任何变化，因此我不必更新这些。
But when I compute the height, update height
但是当我计算高度时，更新高度
at the beginning of the listing assumes
在列表的开头假设
that the height of the children is correct.
孩子的身高是正确的。
So when I compute the height of my mode,
因此，当我计算模式高度时，
the height of the children has to be updated.
孩子们的身高必须更新。
So if I call Update Height of B first,
因此，如果我先调用B的更新高度，
I already know that this might have changed,
我已经知道这可能已经改变，
so whatever answer I get is bogus.
所以我得到的答案都是假的。
So this doesn't work and I have to do this.
所以这行不通，我必须这样做。
This is rotation.
这是旋转。
That's rebalancing.
那是重新平衡。
One more trick to rebalancing.
再平衡的另一招。
So we talked about rebalancing the subtree at one node.
因此，我们讨论了在一个节点上重新平衡子树的问题。
What's missing from this picture?
该图片缺少什么？
AUDIENCE: So you check it on all levels?
听众：那么您在所有级别上都进行检查吗？
PROFESSOR: Yeah.
教授：是的。
So I made some changes here.
所以我在这里做了一些更改。
My tree might look happy starting from here on,
从这里开始，我的树可能看起来很幸福，
but if I did an insertion or a deletion,
但是如果我进行了插入或删除，
heights changed all the way up, so I
高度一路上升，所以我
have to go all the way up and do more rebalancings potentially.
必须全力以赴，并可能进行更多的重新平衡。
And that's it.
就是这样。
These are AVLs.
这些是AVL。
Any other questions?
还有其他问题吗？
Did you guys get them?
你们得到了吗？
Do they make more sense now?
他们现在更有意义吗？
AUDIENCE: Yes.
听众：是的。
PROFESSOR: OK.
教授：好的。
Good.
好。
You'll have to play with them on the next Pset.
您必须在下一个Pset上与它们一起玩。
AUDIENCE: By "play," what do you mean?
听众：“玩”是什么意思？
PROFESSOR: Well, you're not writing it from scratch.
教授：嗯，您不是从头开始编写的。
You have to modify existing code.
您必须修改现有代码。
AUDIENCE: What are we going to make it do?
听众：我们要怎么做？
PROFESSOR: So you'll have to keep track of something other
教授：所以您必须跟踪其他内容
than heights.
比高度。
You'll have to keep track of a new value.
您必须跟踪新值。
AUDIENCE: Oh, like the minimum or something?
听众：哦，像最低价一样吗？
PROFESSOR: Or something, yeah.
教授：是的，是的。